# Siddharth Verma

© https://siddharthverma314.github.io | ■ siddharthverma314@gmail.com

### About me

I am an ML Researcher with deep expertise in training state-of-the-art LLMs. I write performant low-level code to train models across thousands of GPUs. I also conduct research in both academic and industrial settings, resulting in publications in prestigious venues like NeurIPS and ACL.

Languages: Python, Haskell, Rust, Java, SQL, C, Go, CUDA, RISC-V

Skills: Language Modeling, LLM Pretraining, Reinforcement Learning, Neural Networks, Statistics Technologies: Pytorch, JAX, OpenAl Triton, Pallas, Docker, NixOS, Unix/Bash, Git, Google Cloud

# **Experience**

#### **GDM Research Engineer**

□ Aug 2024-Current

- Wrote performant low level kernels for experimental attention variants using pallas
- Investigated numerical instability in MoE implementation and its effects on pretraining and RL

#### Research Engineer

- Character.ai New York NY
   Contributed to all aspects of LLM pretraining from fundamental research to performant implementations
- Discovered the relation between attention and intelligence in LLMs and its corresponding scaling laws
- Designed scaling laws to predict a 5 order-of-magnitude extrapolation in validation loss with tight error bounds
- Implemented multiple MoE variants for our flagship model trained across our entire cluster of GPUs
- Investigated the non-causality of Expert Choice MoEs and when this affects model performance

#### **Senior Machine Learning Engineer**

- Square Boston MA
   Finetuned open-source LLMs on merchant-buyer conversations to suggest replies to incoming messages
- Conducted an online A/B test and demonstrated a 5% increase in suggestion acceptance rate
- Designed and implemented a multi-task training system to incorporate classification tasks into an LLM
- Instruction finetuned FLAN-T5 on internal data and evaluated performance against individual classifiers

#### **AI Resident**

- Meta (Facebook)
   To Aug 2021-Sep 2022
   Wrote code to process 1TB of multimodal data using Rust and Parquet for a 20x speedup against Python
- Automated the training LLMs of up to 13B parameters on large multi-node clusters with up to 64GPUs
- Evaluated whether training on explanations improve reasoning capabilities of LLMs, and found that explanations mostly benefit mathematical reasoning
- Analyzed effect of masking rates and masking strategies in multimodal learning, showing that increasing masking rate nullifies effects of different masking strategies

### **Undergraduate Researcher at Robotic AI and Learning Lab**

■ Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research Lab. ♥ Berkeley CA
• Worked with Prof. Sergey Levine and Prof. Chelsea Finn on RL and NLP in domains of robotics and chatbots

- Designed and implemented a multi-agent RL algorithm to learn composable locomotive skills without manual environment resets, subsequently using them to solve a maze. Published at NeurIPS
- Used Offline RL to finetune LLMs to bargain on craigslist items, beating supervised learning in human evals across all metrics. Accepted as oral presentation at NAACL

# Education

#### **BA Computer Science & Music**

♥ UC Berkeley ♥ GPA: 3.965, Major: 4.0 □ Aug 2017-May 2021 • Courses: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Probability and Random Processes, Theoretical Statistics\*, Information Theory and Coding\*, Security, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Algorithms, Real Analysis \* indicates graduate level